<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-01T20:03:12-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Baby Black Box</title><subtitle>Baby Black Box is an honest blog for first-time and veteran parents.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Things I Did to Avoid People Asking Me to Hold My Baby</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/avoid-people-asking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Things I Did to Avoid People Asking Me to Hold My Baby" /><published>2023-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/avoid-people-asking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/avoid-people-asking/"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Baby wear!!!</strong> This means slings, pouches, backpacks… Honestly it’s amazing!!! And the more kids you have, the more acceptable it is.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>The sit with us.</strong> Put a blanket down and sit with the baby on the floor so they can play. When someone approaches with that “I-want-to-hold-your-baby look,” just say “oh hey, sit with us.” It’s very effective. It’s about riding the wave, not fighting it.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>The poop change.</strong> Thanks to the poop machines, I can use the “oh let me change him/her,” then circle to another group afterward. I also don’t let anyone change my kids either other than my husband and me. Sensing a pattern? Like I said, you do you. Listen to your good judgment.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>The “we tried.”</strong> If my kid cries when someone is holding them I <em>100%</em> take my kid back, especially if they say “no, it’s ok - babies need to cry.” The next time they ask to hold them I just say “no, it’s okay.”</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>The practice makes perfect (don’t hold my kid).</strong> Once they start walking, my go-to is  “they need to practice, you can walk with them and make sure they don’t fall.” This is especially effective with those older kids that want to start picking them up.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="new parent" /><category term="first time parent" /><category term="parent" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Be sympathetic but maintain your boundaries.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-black-box-logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-black-box-logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">No One Needs to Hold My Baby</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/no-holding-baby/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No One Needs to Hold My Baby" /><published>2023-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/no-holding-baby</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/no-holding-baby/"><![CDATA[<p>Spring has sprung and family bbq’s and gatherings are around the corner! In this season of family and stork deliveries, the “baby pass around” can get out-of-hand. As a mama who’s not keen on everyone holding her baby, I wanted to share my story with you, because it’s okay not to have your kids passed around like a platter of watermelon.</p>

<p>I was lucky enough to have both of my children during Covid. Yup, lucky. If the pandemic had not shaken up how we gather with friends and family, I would have never been comfortable creating strong boundaries around who holds my kids, especially my newborns.</p>

<p>As a first time mom, I felt pressured and pushed by some family to automatically give permission to hold my daughter. I wanted to be a good daughter-in-law, so I caved. But, this was a mistake.</p>

<p>Just in case, my secret identity is revealed, I won’t call out anyone directly, but some people just don’t know how to safely hold children. I drew the line when a former parent tried to lift my newborn straightup by her arms. I immediately stepped in, but not before my daughter let out a heart-stopping screech. She was fine. I was not. The trust had been broken.</p>

<p>After a successful second delivery, I put my “big girl pants on” and was ready for the inevitable “baby showing.” This time the “sure, you can hold him”s were replaced by the “I’m not ready”s. Because, honestly, I was not ready. I wanted more time to bond with my son. I was too tired and already in a battle zone, trying to survive (again). But most importantly, I did not have the extra energy to spend playing “whack-a-mole,” figuring out which of my family and friends, who I love dearly, did not know how to safely hold a kid but still asked.</p>

<p>I can tell you I was truly at peace with my second, and he has had no problem being held as an infant. My first on the other hand still does not like to sit on people’s laps or hug people. And yes, I do think part of this difference is because she knew I wasn’t at peace with handing her over. So, Mamas and Papas, you do you! Don’t feel pressured to go beyond what your gut says is best for your child.</p>

<p>A very important factor to successfully maintaining your boundaries is the support you have with your partner. I was a bit <em>extra</em> but my husband never pressured me and 100% supported my feelings. Which was honestly a pivotal point in our transition to parenthood and two going to four.</p>

<p>If you want to hear my excuses to avoid handing off my kid:
<a href="/avoid-people-asking">Things I did to avoid people asking</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="new parent" /><category term="first time parent" /><category term="parent" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A very important factor is support and alignment with your partner. I was a bit extra but my husband never pressured me and 100% supported my feelings. This was honestly a pivotal point in our transition to parenthood and going from two to four.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-black-box-logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-black-box-logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Easter Basket Ideas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/easter-baskets/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Easter Basket Ideas" /><published>2023-04-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/easter-baskets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/easter-baskets/"><![CDATA[<p>Happy Easter everybody!!!!
Take a peak inside an Easter basket without refined sugars. My goal in putting together my kids’ baskets is to get them set up for spring/summer activities.
Some of the items I include or look for are:</p>

<p>Sun hats
Sun glasses
Sandals
bubbles
sand toys
water toys
kites
gardening supplies
Markers &amp; notebook
Kid safe scissors (age 2+)
Paint &amp; brushes
Toothbrushes</p>

<p>What I put in the Easter eggs:
Pom poms
Colored pingpong balls
Hair clips and bows</p>

<p>This year I focused on things I could use for sensory/ cognitive play. Plus bows because they were just too cute to pass up.</p>

<p>One of the main benefits i find in creating baskets focused on things my little ones need/ can play with is that it keeps they busy for months and avoids sugar highs and crashes. I also use baskets that can be reused through the year. Those cute Easter baskets are so so tempting but you store it for 364 days for one day of photos.</p>

<p>Quick tip: if you choose to put chocolate and treats in your little ones basket, remember to avoid small hard candies, that can be a choking hazard.</p>

<p>Some quick links to basket items and ideas:</p>

<p>50Pcs/Pack Colored Ping Pong Balls 40mm 2.4g Entertainment Table Tennis Balls Mixed Colors for Game and Advertising https://a.co/d/d0jpLfv</p>

<p>900 PCS Pom Poms, Multicolor Bulk Pom Poms Arts and Crafts, Soft and Fluffy Craft Pom Poms, Assorted Sizes Pompoms, for Arts and Craf… https://a.co/d/8FM5jz6</p>

<p>LAYCOL Baby Swimming Float… https://www.amazon.com/dp/B083W3Q8SL?ref=ppx_pop_mob_ap_share</p>

<p>Baby Toothbrush Set, 6 Pcs Soft… https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01LZAGSIU?ref=ppx_pop_mob_ap_share</p>

<p>Aveeno Baby Continuous Protection… https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07CKM98S4?ref=ppx_pop_mob_ap_share</p>

<p>Kids Sun Hat with Neck Flap -… https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09134NJN5?ref=ppx_pop_mob_ap_share</p>

<p>6 Pairs Kids Gardening Gloves… https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B51HXNTZ?ref=ppx_pop_mob_ap_share</p>

<p>The Children’s Place Unisex-Child and Toddler Boys Buckle Sandals Slide https://a.co/d/irLo0GV</p>

<p>Bubble Machine Omibooy Bubbles for Kids, Outdoor Toys for Toddlers, Automatic Bubble Blower 5000+ Bubbles/min, Kids Toys Bubble Maker, Bubble Machine for Parties, Wedding, Birthday Gifts (Blue) https://a.co/d/37oOmrR</p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="new parent" /><category term="first time parent" /><category term="parent" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Parenting is hard. Sharing is scary. Baby Black Box is where real parents record their stories as they happen "mid-flight" parenthood.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-black-box-logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-black-box-logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">One-Bowl Classic Waffles</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/classic-waffles/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One-Bowl Classic Waffles" /><published>2022-01-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/classic-waffles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/classic-waffles/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h3>

<ul>
  <li>1 1/2 cups warm milk</li>
  <li>1/3 cup melted butter</li>
  <li>2 eggs</li>
  <li>1 teaspoon vanilla extract</li>
  <li>1 teaspoon salt</li>
  <li>4 teaspoons baking powder</li>
  <li>2 tablespoons white sugar</li>
  <li>2 cups all-purpose flour</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="directions">Directions</h3>

<h4 id="step-1">Step 1</h4>
<p>Either leave 1 1/2 cups of milk at room temperature or warm milk for about 30 seconds.  Pour into large metal bowl.</p>

<h4 id="step-2">Step 2</h4>
<p>Melt 1/3 cup of butter in microwave and add to milk.</p>

<h4 id="step-3">Step 3</h4>
<p>Add 2 eggs, 1 teaspoon vanilla extract, 1 teaspoon salt, 4 teaspoons baking powder, and 2 tablespoons white sugar and mix.</p>

<h4 id="step-4">Step 4</h4>
<p>Slowly add and mix 2 cups of all-purpose flour as you mix.</p>

<h4 id="personal-preference">Personal Preference</h4>
<p>We like to cook the waffles on setting 2, which cooks the waffles before it becomes crunchy.  Re-heats well for the kids, without seeming too dry.</p>]]></content><author><name>flightrecorder</name></author><category term="recipe" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quick and easy waffles to make and cleanup.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/waffle.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/waffle.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Going from One to Two</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/going-from-one-to-two/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Going from One to Two" /><published>2021-09-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/going-from-one-to-two</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/going-from-one-to-two/"><![CDATA[<p>How I prepared my oldest for the arrival of our new baby. I found the key to our success was to <em>start as early as possible</em>. I started some of these steps as it became age appropriate, knowing we wanted two under two.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Encouraging independent play</li>
  <li>Teaching words and context</li>
  <li>Promoting helpful behavior</li>
  <li>Refreshing toys to keep her playing</li>
  <li>Link “giving behavior” with new sibling</li>
  <li>Newborn prep</li>
  <li>Consistent 1-on-1 time</li>
  <li>Encourage independence</li>
  <li>Read together</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>1</strong>: I made a very strong effort to encourage independent play multiple times a day, everyday. Especially days and times my husband and I were both home.</p>

<p><strong>2</strong>: I would ask her “where is mama’s baby?” so she could at least hear the word “baby” in reference to something other than her. 
I stopped referring to her as a baby and would correct others in front of her. I would say big girl or toddler. So she would differentiate that she is bigger than the baby.</p>

<p><strong>3</strong>: I would get her involved in diaper changing, because she would already tell me when she was dirty. So, now I would say, “can you bring me the diaper, wipes etc.?”</p>

<p><strong>4</strong>: I removed all the baby toys and packed them away. I did not bring them back out until the baby was a few weeks old.</p>

<p><strong>5</strong>: I had a small “quiet” toy that the baby could give Mary when they met.</p>

<p><strong>6</strong>: I brought out the baby clothes and other newborn items from the closet early, making room for the baby in our life when I was 7-8 months along. This gave our oldest time to adjust to all the new things before the baby arrived. This includes moving the care seat over if the oldest is still in the middle of the car.</p>

<p><strong>7</strong>: Have time for special 1 on 1 time with the oldest with each parent. I focused on things we  could continue after the new baby arrives.</p>

<p><strong>8</strong>: Encourage independence in whatever way you can. Whether it’s asking the oldest to put on their own shoes, get their own jacket, pick out their own clothes, or get their water, it saves you a little bit of time and energy. To make it easier, put their bottles/cups on the counter and whatever other pre-prep you need.</p>

<p><strong>9</strong>: reading reading reading. We love reading and this is something you can do postpartum. It is also something that can help calm the child down. We can create a game out of finding specific books. We also use going to the library as a day trip. That gets the kids out and can keep the readings fresh.</p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="parent" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How two is different than one.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/7.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/7.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Peanut Butter and Prune Teething Crackers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/pb-and-prune-teething-crackers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Peanut Butter and Prune Teething Crackers" /><published>2021-07-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/pb-and-prune-teething-crackers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/pb-and-prune-teething-crackers/"><![CDATA[<p>My little one loves the <a href="/prune-puree-teething-crackers">prune purée teething “crackers”</a> I posted about a month ago. So I used them as a base to start introducing allergies.  I found a great way to make sure she consistently has peanut butter in her diet was to make a nut butter and jelly ( prune purée) bar.</p>

<p>Hope your little one enjoys it!</p>

<h3 id="warning-peanut-butter-and-other-ingredients-can-be-allergens-be-ready-for-any-reactions-and-if-you-have-any-concerns-speak-to-your-healthcare-provider-first"><u>*Warning*: Peanut butter and other ingredients can be allergens. Be ready for any reactions, and if you have any concerns, speak to your healthcare provider first.</u></h3>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h3>

<p><strong><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/K004PTRQ6BJP?leftNavSection=Shopping&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=koalaco-20&amp;linkId=9d7466c26bf11fd9301bc28a952fb5cf&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"><u>Prepared Amazon Shopping List</u></a></strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>1/2 cup peanut butter or nut butter</li>
  <li>1/2 cup prune puree**</li>
  <li>1 cup Oat flour** (or 1/2 cup Oat flour + 1/2 cup baby oatmeal)</li>
  <li>1/2 tsp Cinnamon</li>
  <li>1/2 tsp Vanilla</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="notes">**Notes</h4>
<p>You can make your own:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Prune purée</strong> by placing 6-8 prunes in 1/2 cup of boiling hot water. Let prunes and water sit for about 20 minutes then blend in blender or use immersion blender.</li>
  <li><strong>Oat flour</strong> (choose only one) by placing
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Option 1</strong>: 1 heaping cup of flour into a blender until oats take on a flour like texture.</li>
      <li><strong>Option 2</strong>: 1/2 a cup of oat flour for 1/2 cup of baby oatmeal will up the iron levels and help you use up the baby oatmeal you have leftover 
– 1 heaping cup of flour into a blender until oats take on a flour like texture. 
– Substituting 1/2 a cup of oat flour for 1/2 cup of baby oatmeal will up the iron levels and help you use up the baby oatmeal you have leftover</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="directions">Directions</h3>

<h4 id="step-1">Step 1</h4>

<p>Quick links:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/K004PTRQ6BJP?leftNavSection=Shopping&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=koalaco-20&amp;linkId=9d7466c26bf11fd9301bc28a952fb5cf&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"><u>Helpful Shopping List</u></a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="recipe" /><category term="authenticcooking" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A healthy and common allergen-introducing snack for your infant having teething pains.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/pb-and-prune-puree-crackers.JPG" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/pb-and-prune-puree-crackers.JPG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Prune Puree Teething Crackers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/prune-puree-teething-crackers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prune Puree Teething Crackers" /><published>2021-06-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-06-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/prune-puree-teething-crackers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/prune-puree-teething-crackers/"><![CDATA[<p>As I started my baby-led weaning journey, I realized having quick healthy snacks were a must. I also realized constipation is a common part of babies’ introduction to new foods. So, I worked to create a kid friendly-teething cracker that can be stored in the fridge or freezer. These crackers can be stored easily and tossed in the diaper bag for a fun outing or a snack around the house.</p>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h3>

<p><strong><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/235S4Z50EN10G?leftNavSection=Shopping&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=koalaco-20&amp;linkId=9df084f92ed538516f7898d09968d3fb&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"><u>Prepared Amazon Shopping List</u></a></strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>1/2 cup prune puree**</li>
  <li>1 cup Oat flour** (or 1/2 cup Oat flour + 1/2 cup baby oatmeal)</li>
  <li>1/2 tsp Cinnamon</li>
  <li>1/2 tsp Vanilla</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="notes">**Notes</h4>
<p>You can make your own:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Prune purée</strong> by placing 6-8 prunes in 1/2 cup of boiling hot water. Let prunes and water sit for about 20 minutes then blend in blender or use immersion blender.</li>
  <li><strong>Oat flour</strong> (choose only one) by placing
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Option 1</strong>: 1 heaping cup of flour into a blender until oats take on a flour like texture.</li>
      <li><strong>Option 2</strong>: 1/2 a cup of oat flour for 1/2 cup of baby oatmeal will up the iron levels and help you use up the baby oatmeal you have leftover</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Quick links:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/235S4Z50EN10G?leftNavSection=Shopping&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=koalaco-20&amp;linkId=9df084f92ed538516f7898d09968d3fb&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"><u>Shopping List</u></a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A healthy and nutritional snack for your infant having teething pains.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/prune-puree-crackers.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/prune-puree-crackers.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Vitamin D Drops</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vitamin-d-drops/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vitamin D Drops" /><published>2021-03-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vitamin-d-drops</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vitamin-d-drops/"><![CDATA[<p>I had no idea breast fed babies need vitamin D drops. I did not find out until I was filling out the questionnaire for my child’s one month doctors appointment.  Breast fed babies receive almost all of the nutrition that they need through the mother’s breast milk but they do not receive vitamin D, so it is important that you give them a drop a day.</p>

<p>It seems like such a simple, small thing but in the moment, it seemed like another huge thing to remember. Between being sleep deprived, trying to figure out the breastfeeding thing, pumping to get enough milk for my child, trying to create a freezer stash, taking my vitamins, feeding the family, and making sure the drops are given. I found the easiest way to remember was to store all the vitamin’s together and keep them where you sit or on your table where you eat (if you have other children, don’t forget to keep them up high).</p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="new parent" /><category term="first time parent" /><category term="parent" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Parenting is hard. Sharing is scary. Baby Black Box is where real parents record their stories as they happen "mid-flight" parenthood.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-black-box-logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-black-box-logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tips &amp;amp; Tricks of Welcoming a Baby on a Budget</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/new-baby-tips-and-tricks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tips &amp;amp; Tricks of Welcoming a Baby on a Budget" /><published>2020-11-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/new-baby-tips-and-tricks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/new-baby-tips-and-tricks/"><![CDATA[<p>Congratulations! on your bundle of joy!</p>

<p>As we started planning to extend our family, I combed the internet. I read tons of mom blogs and watched hundreds of hours of vlogs. To me, it all boiled down to everyone’s different budget, space, ideas and values. You will want to spend money on some things and be open to accepting certain things secondhand.</p>

<p>This was our journey:</p>

<p>We joined the local Facebook <em>Buy Nothing</em> group and <em>Nextdoor</em> for our local area. These sites gave us access to free/cheap secondhand items.</p>

<p>As my husband and I were both working very demanding full time jobs and we knew we had a tight budget, we made a list of everything we needed/ wanted. This allowed both of us to look and respond to posts without having to text or call the other.</p>

<p>What we sourced:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Clothes 0-3 and 3-6 months</li>
  <li>Pack and play</li>
  <li>Bouncers</li>
  <li>Walker</li>
  <li>Swings (two different kids)</li>
  <li>Breast pumps and parts</li>
</ul>

<p>My husband is wayyy more tech savvy and loves to search through sites. So we were able to successfully source the entire list above as well as:</p>
<ul>
  <li>a changing table with silicone change pad</li>
  <li>diaper bag</li>
  <li>new elephant basket with new baby toys</li>
  <li>baby blankets</li>
</ul>

<p>It takes time so start early!</p>

<p>I’ll share more posts to help you parent on a budget as your children grow!</p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="parent" /><category term="tips &amp; tricks" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congratulations! on your bundle of joy!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/12.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/12.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Where to Register to Get Baby Samples and Discounts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/where-to-register/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where to Register to Get Baby Samples and Discounts" /><published>2020-09-22T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/where-to-register</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/where-to-register/"><![CDATA[<p>Parenting is hard.  Sharing personal insights is scary.  Baby Black Box is a place where real parents share and record their experiences as they happen “mid-flight” in the journey of parenthood!</p>

<p>title: Where to register to get samples and discounts.</p>

<p>Target- 
Create an online baby registry and make it public. Then go into any target, go to customer service and ask( they are often out) you can also try to get it online through the registry when you make an order over $30 you just pay $.05. With both kids they didn’t scan my phone in store, so I was able to get one in store and one online. 
You also will get a coupon for 15% off. It can be used once in store and once online for items on your registry. Because I have winter babies I put loads of holiday gifts,  clothes for all of us and some food. The discount worked for almost everything. ** even if you do not have a target near you I would still register as you can use the 15% discount once online and it is stacked on other items.</p>

<p>Amazon- create a registry then once someone (could be you) purchase $30 or more you can go in and ship the welcome box to yourself for free. Michael and I both have Amazon accounts and we both could do this. 
Benefits: You received a 15% discount that can be used twice on select leftover baby registry items. The discount becomes available before your due date, so you can stock up on baby items before your bundle arrives. You can also use the second discount after your little one has arrived. There are many more benefits not listed but you do need to read the fine print.</p>

<p>Walmart- create a registry then you have to go to a special Walmart baby box site and enter your information including the url from your registry. Then it will be shipped to you. This box was one of the best baby registry sample box/ packs I received.
 Benefits: No purchase required to qualify for the free samples;  create multiple registries and send them to friends and neighbors addresses to really optimize on the samples.</p>

<p>Buy buy baby-  You just create a registry then walk in and  they will give you the bag. They also do a 15% off coupon for one item and the coupon can be used online.</p>

<p>Formula companies: I plan to breastfeed but based on the research I have found some women struggle to breastfeed especially in the first few days. I signed up for both similac and enfamil just so make sure we have coupons and a small amount of formula in case we need it. 
Similac- if you sign up for Similac’s reward program they will send you coupons that can be used at your local store.</p>

<p>Enfamil- I highly recommend signing up for the Enfamil reward program. Once you sign up, they will send you two small cans of formula and coupons that can be used at your local store.</p>

<p>Links: 
Target- https://www.target.com/gift-registry/create-baby-registryAmazon- https://www.amazon.com/registries?ref_=nav_ListFlyout_findWalmart- https://www.walmart.com/cp/baby-registry/1229485Copy and paste walmart registry URL to https://walmart.cesampling.com/babybox/orderBuy buy baby- https://www.buybuybaby.com/store/page/BabyRegistrySimilac- https://www.similac.com/rewards.htmlEnfamil- https://www.enfamil.com/baby-formula-coupons-samples/</p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="new parent" /><category term="first time parent" /><category term="parent" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Parenting is hard. Sharing is scary. Baby Black Box is where real parents record their stories as they happen "mid-flight" parenthood.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-black-box-logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-black-box-logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>