<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.babyblackbox.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.babyblackbox.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-06T08:31:41-07:00</updated><id>https://www.babyblackbox.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Baby Black Box</title><subtitle>Baby Black Box is an honest blog for first-time and veteran parents.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Protein Waffles</title><link href="https://www.babyblackbox.com/protein-waffles/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Protein Waffles" /><published>2023-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.babyblackbox.com/protein-waffles</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.babyblackbox.com/protein-waffles/"><![CDATA[<p>These are nutrition-rich waffles that are friendly for toddlers and perfect for led weaning.</p>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h3>

<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/NYKCB9IO4YL0?&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=koalaco-20&amp;linkId=56982c68ccb3b27a8e395d0b369ece63&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Convenient Amazon Grocery List</a></p>

<ul>
  <li>2 cups rolled oats</li>
  <li>6 eggs</li>
  <li>2 cups cottage cheese</li>
  <li>Optional: salt and cinnamon to taste</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="directions">Directions</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Put everything in a blender and blend until everything is well combined.</li>
  <li>Put the batter in a waffle iron and cook until golden brown.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="recipe-notes">Recipe notes:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>They are a dense waffle because they’re packed with protein and oats. On their own they are a little bland because there is no sugar in them, so that is where the toppings come in (peanut or nut butter, fruit, or even savory with butter and an extra fried egg or bacon).</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="quick-links">Quick Links:</h3>

<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/NYKCB9IO4YL0?&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=koalaco-20&amp;linkId=56982c68ccb3b27a8e395d0b369ece63&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Grocery List</a></p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="recipe" /><category term="authentic cooking" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Healthy and nutritious waffles for toddlers and led weaning.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.babyblackbox.com/assets/images/protein-waffles.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.babyblackbox.com/assets/images/protein-waffles.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Nutrition-Packed Bread Loaves</title><link href="https://www.babyblackbox.com/nutrition-packed-bread-loaves/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nutrition-Packed Bread Loaves" /><published>2023-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.babyblackbox.com/nutrition-packed-bread-loaves</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.babyblackbox.com/nutrition-packed-bread-loaves/"><![CDATA[<p>These are nutrition-packed bread loaves - perfect for the entire family.</p>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h3>

<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/3RAJJ4R5LWPIS?&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=koalaco-20&amp;linkId=1535acd9aeba67c3d35d950b11544d72&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Convenient Amazon Grocery List</a></p>

<ul>
  <li>2 cups flour (all purpose or whole wheat)</li>
  <li>4 tsps baking powder</li>
  <li>1/2 tsp salt</li>
  <li>1 1/2 cups greek yogurt</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="directions">Directions</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Preheat oven to 375 degrees Fahrenheit.</li>
  <li>Line baking sheet with parchment paper.</li>
  <li>In a large bowl combine all dry ingredients, whisk together.</li>
  <li>Add Greek yogurt to dry ingredients.</li>
  <li>Use a fork to combine.</li>
  <li>Cut dough into 6 pieces.</li>
  <li>Shape dough into bun shape if you want a bagel use thumb to press a hole through the center.</li>
  <li>Place dough on baking sheet.</li>
  <li>Bake 25 minutes and remove to cool.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="quick-link">Quick link:</h3>

<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/3RAJJ4R5LWPIS?&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=koalaco-20&amp;linkId=1535acd9aeba67c3d35d950b11544d72&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Grocery List</a></p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="recipe" /><category term="authentic cooking" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nutrition-packed bread loaves - perfect for the entire family!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.babyblackbox.com/assets/images/bread-loaves.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.babyblackbox.com/assets/images/bread-loaves.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Saving Money Made Easy</title><link href="https://www.babyblackbox.com/saving-money-made-easy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Saving Money Made Easy" /><published>2023-05-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-05-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.babyblackbox.com/saving-money-made-easy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.babyblackbox.com/saving-money-made-easy/"><![CDATA[<p>Disclaimer- I am a conservative person when it comes to sharing my financial information with people but my husband does a ton of research on companies and reminded me that banks and credit card companies sell your spending history to make a profit. Last year, I saved over a hundred dollars on my normal shopping by using these three Apps.</p>

<p><strong>Ibotta</strong> - cash back by scanning your receipt. I normally look through the app to see what they have cash back on and if they have any free/heavily discounted items. The thing I love about this app is once you go shopping you scan your receipt and your savings will be added to your account.  My little loves fruits and Daves jail bread ibotta often has $.20 or more back on any strawberry or blueberry purchese with $1.50 to $2 off jail bread. I can often stack both those offers on top of their $.10 back on any receipt scanned coupon. last summer Ibotta had free oat milk which I do not give my little to drink but I do use it to cook with when I make her homemade oat bars. Once you reach $20 in savings you can trade it out for gift cards or transfer it to your bank account. If you use my link below to sign up and scan your first savings you will get a referral bonus loaded to your account.</p>

<p><strong>Think bigger</strong>: Jan 2022 ibotta had 2% off Safeway receipts and Chase bank had 5% back on grocery stores so you could stack and receive 7% back on your Safeway purchase (some exclusions of course).</p>

<p>Use my referral code <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kpbchie</code> at registration. Sign up via the ibotta app and get a $5 referral bonus</p>

<p><strong>Rakuten</strong> - is a <em>shop through</em> site. Before I make any online purchase I go to my Rakuten app and see if that site has any cash back. They usually have Target, Walmart, Carters, oshkosh bigosh oldnavy and macy’s the percent backs range from 1%-15% back. What I normally do is load what I need to my cart using the company app or website. Before checking out go to Rakuten find the company I need then log into my account and complete the transaction. everything i had in my cart will be there with any company coupons or deals already loaded. This is how I double and triple save on online orders.</p>

<p>Use my link and receive a referral bonus when you complete your first shop through experience.</p>

<p>https://www.rakuten.com/r/MAYAKO63?eeid=44749</p>

<p><strong>Honey</strong> -  is similar to rakuten in the form that you shop through their platform, but it also helps you look for coupons and deals that can be added to your cart. What is nice about honey is you can add an extension to your browser so discounts will pop up as you shop.</p>

<p>Happy shopping everyone!</p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="new parent" /><category term="first time parent" /><category term="parent" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here are some creative ways to save a little at a time.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1579621970563-ebec7560ff3e?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1742&amp;q=80" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1579621970563-ebec7560ff3e?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1742&amp;q=80" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Things I Did to Avoid People Asking Me to Hold My Baby</title><link href="https://www.babyblackbox.com/avoid-people-asking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Things I Did to Avoid People Asking Me to Hold My Baby" /><published>2023-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.babyblackbox.com/avoid-people-asking</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.babyblackbox.com/avoid-people-asking/"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Baby wear!!!</strong> This means slings, pouches, backpacks… Honestly it’s amazing!!! And the more kids you have, the more acceptable it is.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>The sit with us.</strong> Put a blanket down and sit with the baby on the floor so they can play. When someone approaches with that “I-want-to-hold-your-baby look,” just say “oh hey, sit with us.” It’s very effective. It’s about riding the wave, not fighting it.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>The poop change.</strong> Thanks to the poop machines, I can use the “oh let me change him/her,” then circle to another group afterward. I also don’t let anyone change my kids either other than my husband and me. Sensing a pattern? Like I said, you do you. Listen to your good judgment.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>The “we tried.”</strong> If my kid cries when someone is holding them I <em>100%</em> take my kid back, especially if they say “no, it’s ok - babies need to cry.” The next time they ask to hold them I just say “no, it’s okay.”</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>The practice makes perfect (don’t hold my kid).</strong> Once they start walking, my go-to is  “they need to practice, you can walk with them and make sure they don’t fall.” This is especially effective with those older kids that want to start picking them up.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="new parent" /><category term="first time parent" /><category term="parent" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Be sympathetic but maintain your boundaries.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1544779493-aa344a6ddaac?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=687&amp;q=80" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1544779493-aa344a6ddaac?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=687&amp;q=80" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">No One Needs to Hold My Baby</title><link href="https://www.babyblackbox.com/no-holding-baby/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No One Needs to Hold My Baby" /><published>2023-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.babyblackbox.com/no-holding-baby</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.babyblackbox.com/no-holding-baby/"><![CDATA[<p>Spring has sprung and family bbq’s and gatherings are around the corner! In this season of family and stork deliveries, the “baby pass around” can get out-of-hand. As a mama who’s not keen on everyone holding her baby, I wanted to share my story with you, because it’s okay not to have your kids passed around like a platter of watermelon.</p>

<p>I was lucky enough to have both of my children during Covid. Yup, lucky. If the pandemic had not shaken up how we gather with friends and family, I would have never been comfortable creating strong boundaries around who holds my kids, especially my newborns.</p>

<p>As a first time mom, I felt pressured and pushed by some family to automatically give permission to hold my daughter. I wanted to be a good daughter-in-law, so I caved. But, this was a mistake.</p>

<p>Just in case, my secret identity is revealed, I won’t call out anyone directly, but some people just don’t know how to safely hold children. I drew the line when a former parent tried to lift my newborn straightup by her arms. I immediately stepped in, but not before my daughter let out a heart-stopping screech. She was fine. I was not. The trust had been broken.</p>

<p>After a successful second delivery, I put my “big girl pants on” and was ready for the inevitable “baby showing.” This time the “sure, you can hold him”s were replaced by the “I’m not ready”s. Because, honestly, I was not ready. I wanted more time to bond with my son. I was too tired and already in a battle zone, trying to survive (again). But most importantly, I did not have the extra energy to spend playing “whack-a-mole,” figuring out which of my family and friends, who I love dearly, did not know how to safely hold a kid but still asked.</p>

<p>I can tell you I was truly at peace with my second, and he has had no problem being held as an infant. My first on the other hand still does not like to sit on people’s laps or hug people. And yes, I do think part of this difference is because she knew I wasn’t at peace with handing her over. So, Mamas and Papas, you do you! Don’t feel pressured to go beyond what your gut says is best for your child.</p>

<p>A very important factor to successfully maintaining your boundaries is the support you have with your partner. I was a bit <em>extra</em> but my husband never pressured me and 100% supported my feelings. Which was honestly a pivotal point in our transition to parenthood and two going to four.</p>

<p>If you want to hear my excuses to avoid handing off my kid:
<a href="/avoid-people-asking">Things I did to avoid people asking</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="new parent" /><category term="first time parent" /><category term="parent" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A very important factor is support and alignment with your partner. I was a bit extra but my husband never pressured me and 100% supported my feelings. This was honestly a pivotal point in our transition to parenthood and going from two to four.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1505497100-73ddb5317fa7?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;q=85&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=srgb&amp;dl=melody-p-cSNumclQixw-unsplash.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1505497100-73ddb5317fa7?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;q=85&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=srgb&amp;dl=melody-p-cSNumclQixw-unsplash.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Double Chocolate Chip Oatmeal Lactation Cookies</title><link href="https://www.babyblackbox.com/double-chocolate-chip-oatmeal-lactation-cookie/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Double Chocolate Chip Oatmeal Lactation Cookies" /><published>2023-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.babyblackbox.com/double-chocolate-chip-oatmeal-lactation-cookie</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.babyblackbox.com/double-chocolate-chip-oatmeal-lactation-cookie/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/extra-breast-pumps-and-parts">I had a very rough start to my breastfeeding journey</a>, on my mission to get my breastmilk to come in and catch up to the needs of my newborn I was desperate to try anything. As a mom on a budget I started to create my own cookie that not only tasted great but gave my body the boost it needed to create “liquid gold” (aka milk). Hope these help your journey, too!</p>

<p>They are perfect to satisfy a chocolate craving or the midnight boost you need as a sleep deprived mom.  If you would like them a bit sweeter try upping the maple syrup to ½ cup.  Happy feeding ladies!!</p>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h3>

<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/3MELVX4S77MGI?&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=koalaco-20&amp;linkId=601b9c2d3c6481261e2e5fd2a90b686b&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Convenient Amazon Grocery List</a></p>

<ul>
  <li>2 tablespoons ground flax seed</li>
  <li>3 tablespoons water</li>
  <li>½ cup coconut oil (melted or softened)</li>
  <li>¼ cup maple syrup (room temperature)</li>
  <li>2 eggs (room temperature)</li>
  <li>1 teaspoon vanilla</li>
  <li>1½ cups all purpose flour</li>
  <li>¼ cup cocoa powder</li>
  <li>1 teaspoon baking soda</li>
  <li>2 teaspoons cinnamon</li>
  <li>½ teaspoon salt</li>
  <li>3 cups oats</li>
  <li>1 cup chocolate chips</li>
  <li>2 tablespoons brewers yeast (optional)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="directions">Directions</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Preheat oven to 350 degrees Fahrenheit.</li>
  <li>Line cookie sheet with parchment paper.</li>
  <li>In a small bowl, combine ground flax seed and water. Set aside.</li>
  <li>In a medium bowl, sift 1½ cups all purpose flour, ¼ cup cocoa powder, 1 teaspoon baking soda, 2 teaspoons cinnamon, ½ teaspoon salt. Mix all together. Add brewers yeast to dry mixture, if desired.</li>
  <li>In a large bowl, combine ½ cup coconut oil, ¼ cup maple syrup, 2 eggs, and 1 teaspoon vanilla.</li>
  <li>Add dry mix to wet mixture. Once combined, fold flax seed and water into dough.</li>
  <li>Stir in oats and chocolate chips, as desired.</li>
  <li>Scoop dough onto your prepared pan. Cookies are on the dense side so they will not spread.</li>
  <li>Bake in oven for 10-12 minutes.</li>
  <li>Remove from oven, let cool and enjoy!!</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="recipe-notes">Recipe notes:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>They can be stored in fridge for 5 days or freeze for up to 3 months. I love to keep them in the freezer and pull them out a few at a time throughout the day. They will thaw quickly on the counter.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="quick-link">Quick link:</h3>

<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/3MELVX4S77MGI?&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=koalaco-20&amp;linkId=601b9c2d3c6481261e2e5fd2a90b686b&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Grocery List</a></p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="recipe" /><category term="authentic cooking" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Healthy oatmeal cookies to support healthy breastfeeding and curb the chocolate craving.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.babyblackbox.com/assets/images/double-chocolate-chip-oatmeal-lactation-cookie.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.babyblackbox.com/assets/images/double-chocolate-chip-oatmeal-lactation-cookie.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lactation Oatmeal Cookies</title><link href="https://www.babyblackbox.com/lactation-oatmeal-cookies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lactation Oatmeal Cookies" /><published>2023-04-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.babyblackbox.com/lactation-oatmeal-cookies</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.babyblackbox.com/lactation-oatmeal-cookies/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/extra-breast-pumps-and-parts">I had a very rough start to my breastfeeding journey</a>, on my mission to get my breastmilk to come in and catch up to the needs of my newborn I was desperate to try anything. As a mom on a budget, I started to create my own cookie that not only tasted great but gave my body the boost it needed to create “liquid gold.” Hope these help your journey, too!</p>

<p>This is a healthy-ish cookie so it is going to be dense and not super sweet. They are perfect to curve the morning hunger strike or a midnight craving of breastfeeding and newborn life. If you would like them a bit sweeter try upping the maple syrup to ½ cup.  Happy feeding ladies!!</p>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h3>

<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/317E48X8J4GZU?&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=koalaco-20&amp;linkId=276e22ce4e5846f5e70de6f5f390bb7f&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Convenient Amazon Grocery List</a></p>

<ul>
  <li>2 tablespoons ground flax seed</li>
  <li>3 tablespoons water</li>
  <li>½ cup coconut oil (melted or softened)</li>
  <li>¼ cup maple syrup (room temperature)</li>
  <li>2 eggs (room temperature)</li>
  <li>1 teaspoon vanilla</li>
  <li>1½ cups all purpose flour</li>
  <li>¼ cup cocoa powder</li>
  <li>1 teaspoon baking soda</li>
  <li>2 teaspoons cinnamon</li>
  <li>½ teaspoon salt</li>
  <li>3 cups oats</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="optional">Optional</h4>
<p>1 cup raisins
1 cup chocolate chips
2 tablespoons brewer’s yeast</p>

<h3 id="directions">Directions</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Preheat oven to 350 degrees Fahrenheit.</li>
  <li>Line cookie sheet with parchment paper.</li>
  <li>In a small bowl, combine ground flax seed and water. Set aside.</li>
  <li>In a medium bowl, sift 1½ cups all purpose flour, ¼ cup cocoa powder, 1 teaspoon baking soda, 2 teaspoons cinnamon, ½ teaspoon salt. Mix all together. Add brewers yeast to dry mixture, if desired.</li>
  <li>In a large bowl, combine ½ cup coconut oil, ¼ cup maple syrup, 2 eggs, and 1 teaspoon vanilla.</li>
  <li>Add dry mix to wet mixture. Once combined, fold flax seed and water into dough.</li>
  <li>Stir in oats and either raisins or chocolate chips, as desired.</li>
  <li>Scoop dough onto your prepared pan. Cookies are on the dense side so they will not spread in the oven.</li>
  <li>Bake in oven for 10-12 minutes.</li>
  <li>Remove from oven, let cool and enjoy!!</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="recipe-notes">Recipe notes:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>They can be stored in fridge for 5 days or freeze for up to 3 months. I love to keep them in the freezer and pull them out a few at a time throughout the day. They will thaw quickly on the counter.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="quick-link">Quick link:</h3>

<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/317E48X8J4GZU?&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=koalaco-20&amp;linkId=276e22ce4e5846f5e70de6f5f390bb7f&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Grocery List</a></p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="recipe" /><category term="authentic cooking" /><category term="sticky" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Healthy oatmeal cookies to support healthy breastfeeding.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.babyblackbox.com/assets/images/lactation-oatmeal-cookie.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.babyblackbox.com/assets/images/lactation-oatmeal-cookie.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Easter Basket Ideas</title><link href="https://www.babyblackbox.com/easter-baskets/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Easter Basket Ideas" /><published>2023-04-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.babyblackbox.com/easter-baskets</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.babyblackbox.com/easter-baskets/"><![CDATA[<p>Happy Easter everybody!!!!</p>

<p>Take a peak inside an Easter basket without refined sugars. My goal in putting together my kids’ baskets is to get them set up for spring/summer activities.
Some of the items I include or look for are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Sun hats</li>
  <li>Sun glasses</li>
  <li>Sandals</li>
  <li>Bubbles</li>
  <li>Sand toys</li>
  <li>Water toys</li>
  <li>Kites</li>
  <li>Gardening supplies</li>
  <li>Markers &amp; notebook</li>
  <li>Kid safe scissors (age 2+)</li>
  <li>Paint &amp; brushes</li>
  <li>Toothbrushes</li>
</ul>

<p>What I put in the Easter eggs:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Pom poms</li>
  <li>Colored pingpong balls</li>
  <li>Hair clips and bows</li>
</ul>

<p>This year I focused on things I could use for sensory/cognitive play. Plus bows, because they were just too cute to pass up.</p>

<p>One of the main benefits to creating baskets focused on things my little ones need (can play with) is that it keeps them busy for months and avoids sugar highs and crashes. I also use baskets that can be reused through the year. Those cute Easter baskets are so so tempting but you store it for 364 days for one day of photos.</p>

<p>Quick tip: If you choose to put chocolate and treats in your little ones basket, remember to avoid small hard candies, that can be a choking hazard. Consider making them some <a href="/pb-and-prune-teething-crackers">PB+Prune Teething Crackers</a></p>

<!-- Some quick links to basket items and ideas:
- 50Pcs/Pack Colored Ping Pong Balls 40mm 2.4g Entertainment Table Tennis Balls Mixed Colors for Game and Advertising https://a.co/d/d0jpLfv
- 900 PCS Pom Poms, Multicolor Bulk Pom Poms Arts and Crafts, Soft and Fluffy Craft Pom Poms, Assorted Sizes Pompoms, for Arts and Craf... https://a.co/d/8FM5jz6

LAYCOL Baby Swimming Float... https://www.amazon.com/dp/B083W3Q8SL?ref=ppx_pop_mob_ap_share

Baby Toothbrush Set, 6 Pcs Soft... https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01LZAGSIU?ref=ppx_pop_mob_ap_share

Aveeno Baby Continuous Protection... https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07CKM98S4?ref=ppx_pop_mob_ap_share


Kids Sun Hat with Neck Flap -... https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09134NJN5?ref=ppx_pop_mob_ap_share

6 Pairs Kids Gardening Gloves... https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B51HXNTZ?ref=ppx_pop_mob_ap_share

The Children's Place Unisex-Child and Toddler Boys Buckle Sandals Slide https://a.co/d/irLo0GV

Bubble Machine Omibooy Bubbles for Kids, Outdoor Toys for Toddlers, Automatic Bubble Blower 5000+ Bubbles/min, Kids Toys Bubble Maker, Bubble Machine for Parties, Wedding, Birthday Gifts (Blue) https://a.co/d/37oOmrR -->]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="new parent" /><category term="first time parent" /><category term="parent" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Easter can be a fun and relaxed day for the family!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.babyblackbox.com/assets/images/easter-basket-2023.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.babyblackbox.com/assets/images/easter-basket-2023.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Infant Iron Levels</title><link href="https://www.babyblackbox.com/infant-iron/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Infant Iron Levels" /><published>2022-04-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-04-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.babyblackbox.com/infant-iron</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.babyblackbox.com/infant-iron/"><![CDATA[<p>As a Mama who has had my own personal struggles with iron, I did loads of research to make sure I was aware of the ways my kid needed and would absorb iron.</p>

<p>Iron is a common mineral required by the body for healthy growth and development.</p>

<p>I knew I wanted to be a mom who made most of my kids’ food at home to avoid extra additives, but it’s important to provide balanced meals with all the necessary vitamins and minerals. I found iron is one of the main beneficial additives that companies use because it is so important for children.</p>

<p><strong>The foods I try first:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Leafy greens- Spinach</li>
  <li>Broccoli</li>
  <li>Red meat</li>
  <li>Poultry</li>
  <li>Oats</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Common allergens with good iron levels:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Nuts- checking hazard so nut butter is a great way to add this to your littles diet</li>
  <li>Tofu- soy allergy</li>
  <li>Eggs</li>
</ul>

<p>I highly recommend an 18 month blood draw for common vitamin deficiencies and nutrition blood tests. A blood draw is always terrifying and horrible to go through as a parent but it will alert you if you need to put your little one on a supplement. Littles grow so fast both physically and mentally, so they are burning iron at a very high rate. If your little does test low in iron, it’s ok. My husband and I had to put my oldest on a supplement even though I did all of these things. So, please make sure you get your little ones checked.</p>

<p>Keep an eye out on the creative ways I add iron rich foods to our daily meals!</p>

<h3 id="references">References</h3>

<ul>
  <li>https://www.cdc.gov/breastfeeding/breastfeeding-special-circumstances/diet-and-micronutrients/iron.html#:~:text=Iron%20is%20necessary%20to%20make,during%20infancy%20and%20early%20childhood.</li>
  <li>https://www.healthdirect.gov.au/foods-high-in-iron</li>
  <li>https://www.amazon.com/NovaFerrum-Pediatric-Supplement-Infants-Toddlers/dp/B00BTMKDUU/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?keywords=iron+supplements+for+kids&amp;qid=1682965646&amp;sprefix=iron+supp%2Caps%2C167&amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;psc=1&amp;smid=A39CY02RNJQJS9&amp;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEzNkpFSk8zOVRaUDA5JmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwMzQwOTYzRUlYQUdZU0xKRUwyJmVuY3J5cHRlZEFkSWQ9QTA0MjA5NDRBWVMzVEtMMTlXMCZ3aWRnZXROYW1lPXNwX2F0ZiZhY3Rpb249Y2xpY2tSZWRpcmVjdCZkb05vdExvZ0NsaWNrPXRydWU=</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="new parent" /><category term="first time parent" /><category term="parent" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Make sure to check your infant's iron levels.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.babyblackbox.com/assets/images/baby-black-box-logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.babyblackbox.com/assets/images/baby-black-box-logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cuddle Cuddle Cuddle</title><link href="https://www.babyblackbox.com/cuddle-cuddle-cuddle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cuddle Cuddle Cuddle" /><published>2022-03-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-03-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.babyblackbox.com/cuddle-cuddle-cuddle</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.babyblackbox.com/cuddle-cuddle-cuddle/"><![CDATA[<p>You cannot “spoil” your baby when they are a few months old. I feel like it is all about socially treating a baby like they are a teenage. You can find blogs and videos of people potty training a 3 month old and sleep training at 3-4 months. To the parents out there who are wanting to contact sleep, cuddle and hold their baby - DO IT!!! There is time later to sleep train, potty train, and do the laundry. I tell my husband all the time, she will only be this old today so we need to soak it in. Plus, nothing beats that sweet little kiss you can give your little ones head when they are asleep.</p>]]></content><author><name>koalamama</name></author><category term="new parent" /><category term="first time parent" /><category term="parent" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cuddle today. Laundry tomorrow.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1450778869180-41d0601e046e?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1586&amp;q=80" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1450778869180-41d0601e046e?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1586&amp;q=80" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>